<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Molecule Substructure Filter</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Applies a number of substructure filters to an input RDKit Mol column.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Applies a substructure filter to an input RDKit Mol column. The patterns
            are given as SMARTS, SMILES, SDF or RDKit molecules in the second input table. You can choose either a minimum number
            of patterns to match or to require that all match.
        </intro>

        <tab name="Options">
            <option name="RDKit Mol column">Select the column from the first input table that contains the RDKit molecules</option>
            <option name="Query Mol column">Select the column from the second input table that contains the query molecules.
                Acceptable types are SMARTS, SMILES, SDF and RDKit Mol.</option>
            <option name="Use chirality">If this is set, information about stereochemistry will be used in the substructure search.</option>
            <option name="Matches">Select the minimum number of patterns that must match for each molecule so that it is
                included in the first output table</option>
            <option name="New column name for matching substructures">Enter here the name of the new column that will contain
                a list of all matching substructure row indices</option>
           </tab>
           <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Fingerprint screening threshold">Substructure search performance can be improved using fingerprints.
                This makes sense when there are many different query molecules and a lot of input molecules. In this case
                the node can pre-calculate fingerprints once for all input and query molecules and do some pre-screening for
                substructure matching. The fingerprint screening threshold value defines the number of query molecules (table 2)
                that must be present in order to enable fingerprint calculation and pre-screening.
                Set it to 0 to disable fingerprint screening completely for this node. Set it to -1 to always
                use the RDKit Nodes default behavior (the standard setting).</option>
            <option name="Use row keys as substructure match information">
                The column for matching substructure indices contained (for historic reasons) the row index, which turned out
                not to be too useful. Click this flag to use row keys instead, which is today the default for new nodes.</option>
           </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Molecules">Table with RDKit molecules</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Query Molecules">Table with SMARTS, SMILES, SDF or RDKit Mol molecules to use as queries</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Molecules matching filter">Molecules matching the substructure query</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Molecules not matching filter">Molecules not matching the substructure query</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
