<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Diversity Picker</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Picks diverse rows.
	</shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Picks diverse rows from an input table based on tanimoto distance between fingerprints.
        The picking is done using the MaxMin algorithm 
        (Ashton, M. et. al., Quant. Struct.-Act. Relat., 21 (2002), 598-604).
        The algorithm is quite fast, even for large datasets, but note that runtime
        increases rapidly with the number of rows to be picked.</intro>
		
		<tab name="Options">
	        <option name="Molecule or fingerprint column (table 1)">The column containing the molecules or fingerprints to pick from.
	        	If molecules are selected their fingerprints will be calculated automatically with Morgan, Radius 2, 2048 bit length.</option>
	        <option name="Molecule or fingerprint column to bias away from (table 2)">
	        	The column containing molecules or fingerprints to bias away from. This option has the effect of 
	        	seeding the diversity pick: Molecules selected will be diverse with respect to these biasing molecules 
	        	as well as each other. If molecules are provided as input their fingerprints will be calculated automatically based on input of table 1. 
	        	If table 1 has fingerprints with unknown settings this calculation will fail. In this case please regenerate fingerprints in table 1 with 
	        	the RDKit Fingerprint Node or select a compatible fingerprint column in table 2 instead of a molecule column.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Number to pick">Number of diverse rows to pick.</option>
	        <option name="Random seed">Random number seed to use.</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Molecules or Fingerprints">Table with either molecule or fingerprints for diversity picking</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Additional Input to Bias Away From">Table with either molecules or fingerprints to bias away from</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Diverse rows">The results of the diversity pick</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
