<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Add Conformers</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Creates a new table with multiple conformers per input molecule.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Creates a new table with multiple conformers per input molecule. Each conformer is a copy of the molecule with different coordinates assigned.			Each conformer row is mapped back to the input table molecule with an identifier - usually the row id - taken from an input table column.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Input">
	        <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules.</option>
	        <option name="Reference column (e.g. an ID)">The input column with reference data to be assigned to conformer rows.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Conformer Calculation">
	        <option name="Number of conformers">Number of conformers to be generated.</option>
	        <option name="Maximum number of tries to generate conformers">Maximum number of tries that the RDKit will use to generate conformers.</option>
	        <option name="Random seed">A random seed to initialize random number generator.</option>
	        <option name="RMS threshold for keeping a conformer">The RMS threshold for keeping a conformer.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output">
	        <option name="Column name for molecules with conformers">The output column with the generated conformers.</option>
	        <option name="Column name for copied reference data">The output column with reference data taken from the input table.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
	        <option name="Use random coordinates as a starting point instead of distance geometry">
	        	Setting this flag will use random coordinates as a starting point instead of distance geometry.</option>
	        <option name="Multiplier for the size of the box for random coordinates">
	        	Specifies a multiplier for the size of the box for random coordinates.</option>
	        <option name="Perform a cleanup using UFF (Universal force field) after calculation">
	        	Set this flag to perform cleanup with UFF after the conformer's calculation.
	        	Just clear this flag to output unprocessed conformers in case you want to perform other processing on them 
	        	before cleaning them up with a force field.</option>
       	</tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with RDKit Molecules">Input table with RDKit Molecules</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Result table">Table with calculated conformers</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
