<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Add Conformers</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Creates a new table with multiple conformers per input molecule.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Creates a new table with multiple conformers per input molecule. Each conformer is a copy of the molecule with different coordinates assigned. Each conformer row is mapped back to the input table molecule with an identifier - usually the row id - taken from an input table column.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Input">
            <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules.</option>
            <option name="Reference column (e.g. an ID)">The input column with reference data to be assigned to conformer rows.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Conformer Calculation">
            <option name="Number of conformers">Number of conformers to be generated.</option>
            <option name="Maximum number of tries to generate conformers">Maximum number of tries that the RDKit will use to generate conformers.</option>
            <option name="Random seed">A random seed to initialize random number generator.</option>
            <option name="RMS threshold for keeping a conformer">The RMS threshold for keeping a conformer.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output">
            <option name="Column name for molecules with conformers">The output column with the generated conformers.</option>
            <option name="Column name for copied reference data">The output column with reference data taken from the input table.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Enforce the preservation of input chirality">
                Ensures that the chirality/bond stereochemistry specified in the input structures 
                is reflected in the conformers.</option>
            <option name="Use experimental torsion angle terms">
                Use data from experimental crystal structures to refine some torsion angles. 
                This uses the "ET" method described in https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5b00654 
                and https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.0c00025 .</option>
            <option name="Experimental torsion angles version">
                Choose the version of the experimental torsion definitions to use. 
                Possible values are 1 and 2.</option>
            <option name="Use experimental torsion angle terms for small rings">
                Use data from experimental crystal structures to refine some torsion angles in
                 small rings. This uses the "srET" method described in https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.0c00025 .</option>
            <option name="Use experimental torsion angle terms for macrocycles">
                Use data from experimental crystal structures to refine some torsion angles in
                 macrocycles. This uses the method described in https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.0c00025 .</option>
            <option name="Use 1-4 distance bound heuristics for macrocycles">
                Use empirical corrections to modify 1-4 distance bounds in macrocycles. T
                his uses the method described in https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.0c00025 .</option>
            <option name="Use basic knowledge terms">
                Apply "basic knowledge" constraints to planarize atoms which should be planar 
                (e.g. aromatic atoms, conjugated atoms). This uses the "K" method described 
                in https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5b00654 .</option>
            <option name="Force amide bonds to be trans">
                Applies constraints to force amide, ester, and related bonds to have trans configurations.</option>
            <option name="Only use heavy atoms when calculating RMS values">
                When doing RMS pruning only heavy atoms will be used to calculate RMS.</option>
            <option name="Use molecular symmetry when pruning conformers">
                When doing RMS pruning molecular symmetry will be taken into account. Note that for reasons
                 of computation efficiency, when this option is enabled only heavy atoms will be used 
                 in the RMS calculation.</option>
            <option name="Embed fragments separately">
                Embed each of the molecule's fragments individually. Each fragment will be 
                centered at the origin (i.e. the fragments will overlap). When this option is disabled, the 
                fragments will not overlap but attractive inter-fragment interactions (e.g. H-bonds) are not 
                taken into account.</option>
            <option name="Use random coordinates as a starting point instead of distance geometry">
                Setting this flag will use random coordinates as a starting point instead of distance geometry.</option>
            <option name="Multiplier for the size of the box for random coordinates">
                Specifies a multiplier for the size of the box for random coordinates.</option>
            <option name="Perform a cleanup using UFF (Universal force field) after calculation">
                Set this flag to perform cleanup with UFF after the conformer's calculation.
                Just clear this flag to output unprocessed conformers in case you want to perform other processing on them
                before cleaning them up with a force field.</option>
           </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with RDKit Molecules">Input table with RDKit Molecules</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Result table">Table with calculated conformers</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
