<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>RDKit R-Group Decomposition</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Performs an R-Group decomposition for an input RDKit Mol column.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	Performs an R-Group decomposition for an input RDKit Mol column. The algorithm in RDKit was developed in 2018/2019. 
        	It is still in beta state and should be used with care. Results may vary in later versions.
        </intro>

        <tab name="Options">
            <option name="Input Molecules - RDKit Mol column (1st table)">The column containing molecules.</option>
            <option name="Input Scaffolds - Core Input Column (2nd table)">If second table is connected, the column containing cores as RDKit Molecules, SMARTS, SMILES or SDF.</option>
            <option name="Input Scaffolds - Core SMARTS">If no second table is connected, one or multiple new-line separated SMARTS can be defined as the cores to be used.</option>
            <option name="Output Handling - Fail if no matching R-Groups are found">Flag to be set to detect Rx columns that are completely empty and remove them.</option>
            <option name="Output Handling - Fail if no cores are matching at all">Flag to be set to let the node fail if no matches for the provided cores have been found at all.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Labels to recognize R-Groups in scaffolds">Enable or disable one or multiple labels to be used to recognize R-Groups in scaffolds. At least one item need to be picked.</option>
            <option name="Matching strategy">Select how matches shall be found.</option>
            <option name="Labeling for R-Groups output">Enable or disable options now to label R-Groups in the ouput.</option>
            <option name="Core alignment">Select how cores shall be aligned.</option>
            <option name="Match only at R-Groups">Flag to be set to find matches only at R-Groups.</option>
            <option name="Remove hydrogen only R-Groups">Flag to be set to remove R-Groups that consists only of hydrogens from matching.</option>
            <option name="Remove hydrogens post match">Flag to be set to remove all hydrogens in the resulting R-Groups output.</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Molecules">Molecules as RDKit Molecule, SMILES or SDF column</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Scaffolds">Cores as RDKit Molecule, SMARTS, SMILES or SDF column</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Matches with R-Groups">Table with matching core and decomposed R-Groups</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Unmatched molecules">Table with unmatched input rows</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
