<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Salt Stripper</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Node for stripping salts from molecules.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	This node is used for removing salts from RDKit molecules and display the salt stripped 
        	molecules in an additional column in the output table. The user can optionally input salt 
        	definitions into the node. If no salt definition table is provided by the user then the default 
        	salt definitions will be applied.
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Options">
	        <option name="RDKit Mol column">The name of the column in first table containing RDKit molecules for stripping.</option>
	        <option name="New column name">The new name of the column that will contained the salt stripped molecule.</option>
	        <option name="Remove source column">Toggles removal of the input RDKit Mol column in the output table.</option>
	        <option name="Salt definition column">
	        	The name of the column in the optional second table containing 
	        	RDKit molecules as salt definitions (generated usually from SMARTS). This only applies, if a second table is connected.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Keep only largest fragment after salt stripping">Option to reduce the salt stripping outcome even more
	        	keeping only the largest fragment of all remaining fragments. If there are multiple fragments with the same
	        	number of atoms identified as largest fragments, it will keep only the first one it encounters.</option>
       	</tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="RDKit molecules">Table having at least one RDKit molecule type column containing RDKit molecules for stripping.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Salt definitions">Table containing RDKit molecules as salt definitions (generated usually from SMARTS). This table is optional.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Molecules without salts">Table containing the column with salt stripped RDKit molecules.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
