<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="quickform_multisel.png" type="QuickForm">
    <name>Multi Selection QuickForm</name>

    <shortDescription>
      Defines a list of options and allows to select multiple values,
      which are returned in a table and as a comma-separated variable.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
              Defines a list of options and allows to select multiple values,
      		  which are returned in a table and as a variable. 
		      The selection can also be controlled from a quickfrom (WebPortal).
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Label">
          A descriptive label that will be shown in, for instance the web port.
        </option>
        <option name="Description">
          Some lines of description that will be shown in the remote control 
          form, for instance by means of a tooltip.
        </option>
        <option name="Weight">
          A weight value that influences the position of the component in
          the final layout. Lighter elements will be placed at the top, whereas
          heavier items will be placed nearer the bottom. The value is relative
          to the weights of the other components in the workflow (absolute 
          value is not relevant, only the relative comparison to other
          elements).
        </option>
        <option name="Variable Name">
          Variable identifier.
        </option>
        <option name="Variable Value">
          Variable value containing the select value names.
        </option>
        <option name="Column Name">
          Column name to be used for the output table with the selected options.
        </option>
        <option name="Choice List">
          Choices to be added and removed and selected as pre-selected default values.
        </option>
        <option name="Use Only A One-Line GUI Component">
          Option to use a small GUI component for selection of choices.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data table with one column">
            A table with one column and selected values.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
