<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit One Component Reaction</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Applies a reaction to an input RDKit Mol column
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Applies a reaction to an input RDKit Mol column.
            <p>
                The output table contains a row for each product produced by applying the reaction to the inputs.
                <br />
                Each row contains the product molecule, index information, and the reactant molecule that was used.
            </p>
            <p>The reaction can either be defined by a SMARTS pattern in the dialog or by providing a Rxn value at the
                second input port.</p>
        </intro>

        <tab name="Reaction">
            <option name="Reactant RDKit Mol column">The column from the first table containing reactant molecules</option>
            <option name="Rxn column">The column from the second table containing the Rxn</option>
            <option name="Reaction SMARTS">
                A reaction SMARTS describing the reaction.
                <br />
                For a description of the format, please have a look in 
                <a href="http://rdkit.org/docs/RDKit_Book.html#reaction-smarts">The RDKit Book</a>.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Randomization">
            <option name="Randomize reactants">If checked, random reactants will be picked for the reactions.</option>
            <option name="Maximum number of random reactions">Specify here the maximum number of reactions to be calculated.</option>
            <option name="Random seed (or -1 to be ignored): ">Specify here a seed for the random number generator or -1 to use it without a seed.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Other Options">
            <option name="Uniquify products">
                Enable this option to filter out duplicates of products caused by symmetry in molecules.
                Only the first of multiple encountered products will show up in the result table.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Include additional columns from reactant input table into product output table">
                Enable this option in order to select additional data columns from reactant input table to be included into the result table.
            </option>
            <option name="Additional columns from Reactant table">
                Selection of additional data columns from reactant input table.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Molecules">Table with RDKit Molecule column</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Reaction">Table with reaction values; if there are multiple rows only the first row is
            considered</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Product molecules">Product molecules</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
