<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>RDKit SMILES Headers</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Sets, changes and/or retrieves SMILES structures from RDKit table headers, which
        can be made visible using the RDKit Interactive View.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	Sets, changes and/or retrieves SMILES structures from RDKit table headers, which
        	can be made visible using the RDKit Interactive View. It takes a data table
        	as first input and optionally a SMILES definition table as second input. Based on 
        	the column names and SMILES of the second table it will manipulate the SMILES
        	header values of the data table. If a column name in the data table matches 
        	a column name contained in the second input table, its SMILES value will be set 
        	to the SMILES value specified in the second input table. If the new value is empty or missing, the SMILES header 
        	information will be removed from the data table. This node delivers the
        	manipulated table as first output table without changing any data inside the table.
        	As second output table it produces a table with names and SMILES of all columns
        	that have SMILES values set in their headers. This is useful if SMILES values shall
        	be manipulated (e.g. canonicalized) and fed back in later to update the headers.
       	</intro>
        <option name="Column with target column names">The input column of the second table that defines
        	which data table column headers shall be changed.</option>
        <option name="Column with new SMILES values">The new SMILES values to be set for
        	the specified data table columns. An empty or missing cell will remove the SMILES header information.</option>
        <option name="Complete reset of SMILES in all column headers">Flag this option to remove
        	all existing SMILES values from all(!) header columns of the data table before (optionally)
        	setting new SMILES values based on the second input table.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">Table whose SMILES header values shall be set, changed and retrieved.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Optional SMILES definition table">Defines column names and SMILES to be set or changed.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Result data table">Same table as input data table, but with changed SMILES headers.</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Result SMILES definition table">Table with all SMILES headers in result data table.</outPort>
    </ports>    
    
    <views>
    	<view index="0" name="Interactive Table View">
    		Displays the data in a table view. Has the capability to show chemical structures in the headers of the substructure count columns.
    	</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
