<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="fingerprint.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Fingerprint</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Generates hashed bit-based fingerprints for an input RDKit Mol column.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Generates hashed bit-based fingerprints for an input RDKit Mol column and appends
        them to the table. Several fingerprint types are available. Not all settings are used for each type. Settings that
        are not supported by a fingerprint type will be disabled/hidden and will have no effect. The settings a fingerprint gets
        generated with are made available as column properties and can be visualized with the RDKit Interactive View Node.</intro>
        <tab name="Options">
            <option name="Fingerprint type">The type of fingerprint to generate. Choices are:
            <ul>
              <li>Morgan: Circular fingerprint based on the Morgan algorithm and connectivity invariants (ECFP-like)</li>
              <li>FeatMorgan: Circular fingerprint based on the Morgan algorithm and feature invariants (FCFP-like)</li>
              <li>AtomPair: Atom-pair fingerprint</li>
              <li>Torsion: Topological-torsion fingerprint</li>
              <li>RDKit: Daylight-like topological fingerprint</li>
              <li>Avalon: Fingerprint from the Avalon toolkit (http://sourceforge.net/p/avalontoolkit/)</li>
              <li>Layered: An experimental substructure-matching fingerprint (see LayerFlags defintion below)</li>
              <li>MACCS: RDKit implementation of the 166 public MACCS keys</li>
              <li>Pattern: Substructure screening fingerprint based on small number of very generic SMARTS patterns</li>
            </ul>
            More details about different RDKit fingerprint implementations can be found here: 
            https://www.rdkit.org/docs/RDKit_Book.html#additional-information-about-the-fingerprints
            </option>
            <option name="RDKit Mol column">The column containing reactant molecules</option>
            <option name="New Column Name">Name of the fingerprint column in the output table.</option>
            <option name="Remove source column">Toggles removal of the input RDKit Mol column in the output table.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Fingerprint Settings - Num Bits">Number of bits in the fingerprint.</option>
            <option name="Fingerprint Settings - Path length">Path length to be used (Torsion only).</option>
            <option name="Fingerprint Settings - Radius">The radius of the atomic environments considered.</option>
            <option name="Fingerprint Settings - LayerFlags">Which atomic layers should be included. This value is the total of the following 
            	layer flag values: 0x01 pure topology, 0x02 bond order, 0x04 atom types, 0x08 presence of rings, 
            	0x10 ring sizes, 0x20 aromaticity. The default value of 7 (0x01 pure topology + 0x02 bond order + 0x04 atom types) 
            	allows classic substructure searches.</option>
            <option name="Fingerprint Settings - Min Path Length">Minimum length (in bonds) of the paths to be considered.</option>
            <option name="Fingerprint Settings - Max Path Length">Maximum length (in bonds) of the paths to be considered.</option>
            <option name="Rooted Fingerprints - Create rooted fingerprint">Check this option to create a rooted fingerprint based on an atom list.
                This option is not applicable to all fingerprint types.</option>
            <option name="Rooted Fingerprints - Atom list column for rooted fingerprints">
                The column containing the atom lists that are necessary when calculating rooted fingerprints.
                Instead of a list it is also possible to provide an integer column with a single atom index.
            </option>
            <option name="Rooted Fingerprints - Include atoms">Check this option to include the atoms when calculating rooted fingerprints or uncheck to exclude them.</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data">Data with RDKit Mol column</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Output data">Data with fingerprint column</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
