<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="fingerprint.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>RDKit Fingerprint</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Generates fingerprints for an input RDKit Mol column.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>Generates fingerprints for an input RDKit Mol column and appends
		them to the table. Several fingerprint types are available. Not all settings are used for each type. Settings that
		are not supported by a fingerprint type will be disabled/hidden and will have no effect. The settings a fingerprint gets
		generated with are made available as column properties and can be visualized with the RDKit Interactive View Node.</intro>
		<option name="Fingerprint type">The type of fingerprint to generate. Choices are:
		<ul>
		  <li>Morgan: Circular fingerprint based on the Morgan algorithm and connectivity invariants (ECFP-like)</li>
		  <li>FeatMorgan: Circular fingerprint based on the Morgan algorithm and feature invariants (FCFP-like)</li>
		  <li>AtomPair: Atom-pair fingerprint</li>
		  <li>Torsion: Topological-torsion fingerprint</li>
		  <li>RDKit: Daylight-like topological fingerprint</li>
		  <li>Avalon: Fingerprint from the Avalon toolkit (http://sourceforge.net/p/avalontoolkit/)</li>
		  <li>Layered: An experimental substructure-matching fingerprint</li>
		  <li>MACCS: RDKit implementation of the 166 public MACCS keys</li>
		</ul>
		</option>
        <option name="RDKit Mol column">The column containing reactant molecules</option>
		<option name="New Column Name">Name of the fingerprint column in the output table.</option>
		<option name="Remove source column">Toggles removal of the input RDKit Mol column in the output table.</option>
		<option name="Advanced - Fingerprint Settings - Num Bits">Number of bits in the fingerprint.</option>
		<option name="Advanced - Fingerprint Settings - Path length">Path length to be used (Torsion only).</option>
		<option name="Advanced - Fingerprint Settings - Radius">The radius of the atomic environments considered.</option>
		<option name="Advanced - Fingerprint Settings - LayerFlags">Which atomic layers should be included.</option>
		<option name="Advanced - Fingerprint Settings - Min Path Length">Minimum length (in bonds) of the paths to be considered.</option>
		<option name="Advanced - Fingerprint Settings - Max Path Length">Maximum length (in bonds) of the paths to be considered.</option>
		<option name="Advanced - Rooted Fingerprints - Create rooted fingerprint">Check this option to create a rooted fingerprint based on an atom list.
			This option is not applicable to all fingerprint types.</option>
        <option name="Advanced - Rooted Fingerprints - Atom list column for rooted fingerprints">The column containing the atom lists that are necessary when calculating rooted fingerprints.</option>
        <option name="Advanced - Rooted Fingerprints - Include atoms">Check this option to include the atoms when calculating rooted fingerprints or uncheck to exclude them.</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Data">Data with RDKit Mol column</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Output data">Data with fingerprint column</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>
