<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Structure Normalizer</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Checks structures and tries to normalize them, if necessary.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Checks structures and tries to normalize them, if necessary. Structures that are normalized already
            will appear in the first output table. Structures, which need to be normalized will be corrected
            and also put in the first output table. Information about the normalization is made available as
            bit mask (flags) as well as warning messages. Structures, which cannot be normalized or have been
            normalized causing a certain warning flag that the user wants to treat as error are put in the
            second table (&quot;Failed Molecules&quot;). <br></br><br></br>
            The following flags and messages are currently used:
            <ul>
            <li>1 - BAD_MOLECULE, Unable to recognize a molecule (ERROR)</li>
            <li>2 - ALIAS_CONVERSION_FAILED, The atom alias conversion failed (ERROR)</li>
            <li>4 - TRANSFORMED, Structure has been transformed</li>
            <li>8 - FRAGMENTS_FOUND, Multiple fragments have been found</li>
            <li>16 - EITHER_WARNING, A wiggly bond has been removed</li>
            <li>32 - STEREO_ERROR, Stereo chemistry is ambiguously defined (ERROR)</li>
            <li>64 - DUBIOUS_STEREO_REMOVED, A stereo bond has been removed</li>
            <li>128 - ATOM_CLASH, There are two atoms or bonds are too close to each other (ERROR)</li>
            <li>256 - ATOM_CHECK_FAILED, The atom environment is not correct(ERROR)</li>
            <li>512 - SIZE_CHECK_FAILED, The molecule is too big (ERROR)</li>
            <li>1024 - RECHARGED, Structure has been recharged</li>
            <li>2048 - STEREO_FORCED_BAD, Structure has failed: Bad stereo chemistry (ERROR)</li>
            <li>4096 - STEREO_TRANSFORMED, Stereo chemistry has been modified</li>
            <li>8192 - TEMPLATE_TRANSFORMED, Structure has been modified using a template</li>
            </ul>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
            <option name="Input - SDF, SMILES or RDKit Mol column">
                The input column with SDF, SMILES or RDKit Molecules. The latter ones are
                treated as SDF values. SMILES input will be converted internally into mol blocks before the normalization
                is done.</option>
            <option name="Passed Output - Corrected structure column name">
                The name of the column that will contain the original or corrected structure,
                in case that any normalization has been applied.</option>
            <option name="Passed Output - Flags column name">
                The name of the column that will contain the warning flags. This is a bit mask
                where each bit has a certain meaning as described above.</option>
            <option name="Passed Output - Warning messages column name">
                The name of the column that will contain the warning messages associated
                with the flags. The &quot;Passed Molecules&quot; table contains only warnings, which
                are usually associated with a normalization of the input structure.</option>
            <option name="Failed Output - Flags column name">
                The name of the column that will contain the error flags. This is a bit mask
                where each bit has a certain meaning as described above.</option>
            <option name="Failed Output - Error messages column name">
                The name of the column that will contain the error messages associated
                with the flags. The &quot;Failed Molecules&quot; table contains only error that
                prevented the normalization of an input structure. Additionally,
                it may contain also warnings that are treated like an error
                on special request of the user (see Advanced tab).</option>
            <option name="Logfile Output (Optional) - Selected File">
                A logfile can be specified here which logs additional output in case
                of normalizations of structures. It can be used for informal
                purposes only. There is no mapping in the logfile that would
                reveal which line belongs to which structures, hence it is only
                useful if not too many structures are processed.</option>
            <option name="Logfile Output (Optional) - Overwrite if file exists">
                Set this flag to allow overwriting of an existing logfile.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Handling Failures">
            <option name="Special Failures (Optional)">
                Define here, which warning flags should be treated as errors.
                If defined as an error they will appear in the second table (&quot;Failed Molecules&quot; table).
                </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Transformation Configuration File (.trn) (Optional)">
                Let's the user define a customized transformation configuration file.
                The information button shows the configuration that will be used.</option>
            <option name="Augmented Atoms Configuration File (.chk) (Optional)">
                Let's the user define a augmented atoms configuration file.
                The information button shows the configuration that will be used.</option>
            <option name="Advanced Settings (Optional)">
                Configure here certain switches that influence how the Structure
                Normalizer performs its work:
                <ul>
                <li>cc - Check for collisions (of atoms with other atoms or bonds) (DEFAULT SETTING)</li>
                <li>cs - Check stereo conventions (DEFAULT SETTING)</li>
                <li>da - Convert atom text strings to properties</li>
                <li>dg - Convert ISIS groups to S-Groups</li>
                <li>ds - Convert CPSS STEXT to data fields</li>
                <li>dw - Squeeze whitespace out of identifiers</li>
                <li>dz - Strip most of the trailing zeros</li>
                <li>tm - Split off minor fragments (and keep only largest one) (DEFAULT SETTING)</li>
                </ul>
                </option>
            <option name="Additional options (for advanced users only)">
                Normally, there is no need to change these settings. However,
                if you are familiar with the underlying StruChk tool, you may
                define here manually options that are passed directly to the tool
                in addition to the specified switches from above.
                All options must start with a minus, some of them need a subsequent parameter like a file name.
                File names should be surrounded by quotes.
                Multiple options must be separated with new line characters.
                </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with Molecules">Input table with SDF, SMILES or RDKit Molecules</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Passed Molecules">Passed molecules and corrected structures</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Failed Molecules">Failed molecules and error information</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
