<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Adjust Query Properties</name>

    <shortDescription>
        This node allows common adjustments to the matching behavior of molecules that are intended to be used as queries to get better search results.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node allows common adjustments to the matching behavior of molecules that are intended to be used as queries.
            Structure searches based on queries molecules are not always leading to the desired results.
            Often some fine tuning of the query structure helps to increase the search results. RDKit
            offers query properties that can be set explicitly for query molecules to influence a search.
            This node lets the user define the properties to be adjusted.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
            <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with molecules to be used as queries.</option>
            <option name="New column name">The name of the new column which will contain the tuned queries as RDKit Molecules.</option>
            <option name="Remove source column">Set to true to remove the specified source column from the result table.</option>
            <option name="Adjust degree">Enable so that modified atoms have an explicit-degree query added
                based on their degree in the query.</option>
            <option name="Adjust degree flag">Control which atoms have a degree query added.</option>
            <option name="Adjust ring count">Enable so that modified atoms have a ring-count query added
                based on their ring count in the query.</option>
            <option name="Adjust ring count flag">Control which atoms have a ring-count query added.</option>
            <option name="Make atoms generic">Convert atoms to any-atom queries.</option>
            <option name="Make atoms generic flag">Control which atoms are converted to any-atom queries.</option>
            <option name="Make bonds generic">Convert bonds to any-bond queries.</option>
            <option name="Make bonds generic flag">Control which bonds are converted to any-bond queries.</option>
            <option name="Make dummies queries">Enable so that dummy atoms that do not have a specified isotope
                are converted to any-atom queries.</option>
            <option name="Aromatize if possible">Perceive and set aromaticity.</option>
            <option name="Adjust conjugated 5 rings">Sets bond queries in conjugated five-rings to
                SINGLE|DOUBLE|AROMATIC.</option>
            <option name="Set MDL 5 ring aromaticity">Uses the 5-ring aromaticity behavior of the (former) MDL
                software as documented in the Chemical Representation Guide.</option>
            <option name="Adjust single bonds to degree 1 neighbors">Sets single bonds between aromatic atoms and degree one
                neighbors to SINGLE|AROMATIC.</option>
            <option name="Adjust single bonds between aromatic atoms">Sets non-ring single bonds between two aromatic atoms to
                SINGLE|AROMATIC.</option>
            <option name="Use stereo care for bonds">Remove stereochemistry info from double bonds that do not have
                the stereoCare property set.</option>
           </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with molecules to be used as queries">Molecules to be used as queries</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Tuned query molecules">Tuned query molecules</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
