<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Substructure Counter</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Calculates the number of times a query molecule is present in the input molecule.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
               This node is used to calculate the number of times a particular query molecule is present in an input molecule.
            The number of times the query molecule present in the input molecule can be repeated.
            It is possible to choose the unique number of times the query molecule is present in the input molecule.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Input">
            <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules.</option>
            <option name="Input Query Column">The name of the column in second table containing query molecules which will act as substructure for the input molecules</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Search">
            <option name="Count Unique Matches Only?">This option is selected if user requires unique matches of the query molecule in an input molecule.</option>
            <option name="Use chirality">If this is set, information about stereochemistry will be used in the substructure search.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output">
            <option name="Instead of query molecules use names as result header titles (and tags)">
                Select this option to allow the node to use names specified in the query table
                as column title for the resulting count columns and tags. If disabled, it will use the
                SMILES or SMARTS value as title.
            </option>
            <option name="Column with names for header titles">
                If the last option is enabled the column with the query names must be selected here.
            </option>
            <option name="Add total hits count column">
                Select this option to add a column that contains the accumulated hits count of all hits.
            </option>
            <option name="New column name for total hits count">
                If the last option is enabled the name for the new column must be specified here.
            </option>
            <option name="Add column with tags for matching queries">
                Select this option to add a column that contains a collection of all tags (SMILES, SMARTS values or tags taken from header titles column)
                for the matching queries. This can be useful for further processing.
            </option>
            <option name="New column name for tags">
                If the last option is enabled the name for the new column must be specified here.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input molecule table">Table with input molecule column</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Query molecule table">Table with input query column</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Number of substructures">Input molecule table with one additional column for each row in the query molecule table.
                The new columns added contain the number of times that a query molecule is found in the molecule.</outPort>
    </ports>

    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Interactive Table View">
            Displays the data in a table view. Has the capability to show chemical structures in the headers of the substructure count columns.
        </view>
    </views>

</knimeNode>
