<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>RDKit Molecule Catalog Filter</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Filters a list of molecules by applying filters defined in standard catalogs: PAINS, PAINS A, PAINS B, PAINS C, BRENK, NIH, ZINC or ALL.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Filters a list of molecules by applying filters defined in standard catalogs: PAINS, PAINS A, PAINS B, PAINS C, BRENK, NIH, ZINC or ALL.
        The second output table lists very detailed the reasons why a molecule was filtered out.
        It gives the option to generate one or more atom lists columns with the indexes of the atoms
        that were responsible for a filter rule to match. This makes it possible to use the 
        RDKit Molecule Highlighting node to color the associated substructures, even with different
        colors based on the catalog that defined the rule.
        </intro>
        <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules.</option>
        <option name="Filter catalogs to apply">Define which filter catalogs shall be used for filtering.</option>
        <option name="Prefix for result columns">Column names for the second (filtered out) table are
        automatically assigned, but a prefix can be assigned, which makes it possible to 
        run this node sub-sequentially with different filters.</option>
        <option name="Atom list handling">Option to tell, if atom lists of matching filters shall be generated or not,
        	and if they should be combined in a single column for all matches, or if separate atom list
        	columns should be generated, one per filter catalog.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with RDKit Molecules">Input table with RDKit Molecule to be filtered</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Good molecules">Molecules which have not been filtered out</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Bad molecules">Molecules which have been filtered out</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
