<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Two Component Reaction</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Applies a reaction to two RDKit Mol columns.
	</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Applies a reaction to two RDKit Mol columns.
            <p>
                The output table contains a row for each product produced by applying the reaction to the inputs.
                <br />
                Each row contains the product molecule, index information, and the reactant molecules that were used.
            </p>
            <p>The reaction can either be defined by a SMARTS pattern in the dialog or by providing a Rxn value at the
                third input port.</p>
        </intro>

		<tab name="Reaction">
	        <option name="Reactants 1 RDKit Mol column">The column containing the first reactant molecules</option>
	        <option name="Reactants 2 RDKit Mol column">The column containing the second reactant molecules</option>
	        <option name="Rxn column">The column from the second table containing the Rxn</option>
	        <option name="Reaction SMARTS">
	            A reaction SMARTS describing the reaction.
	            <br />
	            For a description of the format, please see Chapter 2 of the
	            <a href="http://rdkit.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/rdkit/trunk/Docs/Book/RDKit_Book.pdf">RDKit Book</a>.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Randomization">
	        <option name="Randomize reactants">If checked, random reactants will be picked for the reactions.</option>
	        <option name="Maximum number of random reactions">Specify here the maximum number of reactions to be calculated.
	        	Note: When picking a number higher than a million and switching on Matrix expansion this may cause memory issue and freeze KNIME.</option>
	        <option name="Random seed (or -1 to be ignored): ">Specify here a seed for the random number generator or -1 to use it without a seed.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Other Options">
	        <option name="Uniquify products">
	        	Enable this option to filter out duplicates of products caused by symmetry in molecules.
	        	Only the first of multiple encountered products will show up in the result table.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Do matrix expansion">If checked, each reactant 1 will be combined with each reactant 2
	            yielding the combinatorial expansion of the reactants. If not checked, reactants 1 and 2 will be combined
	            sequentially, with the shorter list determining the number of output rows.</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Reactant 1">Data with RDKit Mol column</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Reactant 2">Data with RDKit Mol column</inPort>
        <inPort index="2" name="Reaction">Table with reaction values; if there are multiple rows only the first row is
            considered</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Product molecules">Product molecules</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
