<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Other" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit SDF Difference Checker</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Compares SDF strings of two columns and fails if differences are found.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Compares SDF strings of two columns and fails if differences are found. A tolerance range can be defined
            for comparing floating point numbers. There is no "real" SDF logic in this node. It simply does the following:
            First it removes all operating system specific characters and removes all white spaces that are found in a row
            replacing them by a single space. Then it walks through all remaining items which are now separated by single spaces and compares them.
            If a numeric value is encountered that includes a floating point, it will try to parse it as a double number,
            and if this succeeds for both sides, it will compare the numbers with each other. For the comparison
            we can specify a tolerance.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
            <option name="SDF column (table 1)">The first input column with SDF strings.</option>
            <option name="SDF column (table 2)">The second input column with SDF strings.</option>
            <option name="Tolerance for all floating point numbers">Every floating point number in the SDF string to be compared
                is allowed to have this tolerance range.</option>
            <option name="Fail on first encountered difference">Set to true to fail immediately when the first difference has been encountered.
                Set to false to walk through the tables until the end to find more differences (console output) and then fail and
                report the first encountered difference.</option>
            <option name="Limit console output about different rows to">To avoid that the console gets cluttered with all
                differences that may be found you may set a limit here. Default is 3.</option>
           </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input first table with SDF strings to be compared">SDF strings to be compared</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Input second table with SDF strings to be compared">SDF strings to be compared</inPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
