<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>RDKit Molecule Extractor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Splits up fragment molecules contained in a single RDKit molecule cell and extracts these molecules into separate cells.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	Splits up disconnected fragment molecules contained in a single RDKit molecule cell 
        	and extracts these molecules into separate cells, also sanitizing these molecules if desired. 
        	If the input cell is empty (missing), the input cell will be used as result with the 
        	appropriate reference column. If the input molecule contains only one fragment it will
        	result in a single row. The node can either be used with an input table or based on 
        	flow variable input for the molecules and their format. Supported molecule formats are
        	RDKit Mol cells (when connecting an input table), SMILES, MOL and SDF. <br></br>
        	Please be aware that auto-conversion (e.g for SMILES input) may fail when connecting an input table. <br></br>
        	The Advanced Tab offers different options to treat conversion failures, empty input cells 
        	and zero-atom molecules (empty molecules). You may configure the node to fail, to generate empty cells
        	with or without warning, or to skip the input with or without warning.<br></br>
        	The node can be used for instance after a Quickform Molecule Input node, which brings up a sketcher in the
        	KNIME Web Portal. When the user draws multiple molecules at once this node will split up the users
        	input into multiple molecules.  
        </intro>
        <option name="Table Input - RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules, which may contain multiple disconnected fragments to be extracted.</option>
        <option name="Table Input - Reference column (e.g. an ID)">The column to be used as reference column. Its values are assigned to 
        	 to the cells with the extracted molecules. You may use the Row ID here or set it to None, in which case the reference column will not be added.</option>
        <option name="Variable/Data Input - Molecules">A textual representation of the molecules to be split. Usually, you will 
        	 attach a flow variable to control this setting, e.g. coming from a Molecule Sketcher. This setting will only
        	 be used, if no table is connected.</option>
        <option name="Variable/Data Input - Format">The format of the molecules: MOL, SDF or SMILES are supported. 
             This setting will only be used, if no table is connected.</option>
        <option name="Output - Column name for extracted molecules">The name to be used for the new column used to store extracted molecules.</option>
        <option name="Output - Column name for copied reference data">The name to be used for the new reference column used to store the reference values.</option>
        <option name="Advanced - Sanitize fragments">Flag to determine, if fragments shall be sanitized when being extracted. 
        	Selecting this option may lead to additional fragmentation errors. Default is false.</option>
        <option name="Advanced - How to react on conversion errors">Define here, how the node shall behave, if 
        	an input molecule to be processed could not be converted into an RDKit molecule. Usually, this is the case
        	if the molecule is invalid. By default, the node
        	will generate a missing cell and no warning.
        	If conversion requires special treatment, you may use the RDKit From Molecule node
        	to perform the conversion before executing this node. It offers different options for conversion.</option>
        <option name="Advanced - How to react on empty (missing) cells">Define here, how the node shall behave, if 
        	an empty (missing) cell is used as input. By default, the node
        	will generate a missing cell and no warning.</option>
        <option name="Advanced - How to react on empty (zero atom) molecules">Define here, how the node shall behave, if 
        	an empty molecule is used as input. This means that the molecule has zero atoms. By default, the node
        	will generate a missing cell and no warning.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with RDKit Molecules">Input table with RDKit Molecules, which may contain disconnected fragment molecules.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Result table with extracted RDKit Molecules">Output table with extracted fragment molecules.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
