<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Open 3D Alignment</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
    Aligns the 3D model of two structures based on their shape and three-dimensional conformation.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	    	Aligns the 3D model of two structures based on their shape and three-dimensional conformation. The structure 
	    	taken from table 1 will be aligned to a reference structure taken from table 2. 
	    	If reference table 2 contains only a single row all query molecules of table 1 will be aligned to this single structure.
        	If reference table 2 contains more than one row, the alignment will be performed row by row until one of the tables has no more
        	rows to process. If the passed in molecules have no conformation, it will be calculated.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
	        <option name="Query RDKit Mol column (table 1)">The input column of table 1 with RDKit Query Molecules to be aligned.</option>
	        <option name="Reference RDKit Mol column (table 2)">The input column of table 2 with RDKit Reference Molecules to base
	        	the alignment on. If the table contains only a single row all query molecules of table 1 will be aligned based on this.
	        	If the table contains more than one row, the alignment will be performed row by row until one of the tables has no more
	        	rows to process.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for aligned molecule">The name of the new column, which will contain the aligned molecule.</option>
	        <option name="Remove source column">Set to true to remove the specified source column of table 1 from the result table.</option>
	        <option name="New molecule column name">The name of the new column, which will contain the aligned molecule.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for Row IDs of reference used molecule">The name of the new column, which will contain the row id of the used reference molecule of table 2.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for RMSD information">The name of the new column, which will contain the root-mean-square deviation (RMSD) for the aligned molecule.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for score information">The name of the new column, which will contain the score for the aligned molecule.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
	        <option name="Allow reflection">Set to true to allow reflection of structure parts during the alignment process.</option>
	        <option name="Maximal number of iterations">The maximal number of iterations used in the alignment process.</option>
	        <option name="Accuracy">Determines how accurate the alignment process shall work (0 - most accurate, 3 - least accurate).</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with RDKit Query Molecules">The table with the molecules to be aligned.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Input table with RDKit Reference Molecules">The table with the reference molecules to base the alignment on.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Result table">Aligned molecules</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
