<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>RDKit Molecule Highlighting</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Creates an SVG column showing a molecule with highlighted atoms and bonds based on information in the input table. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	Creates an SVG column showing a molecule with highlighted atoms and bonds based on information in the input table. 
	        A molecule column as well as column(s) with a list of the atom and/or bond indexes to be highlighted 
	        needs to be provided. The node lets the user define colors to be applied for the highlighting. 
	        If highlighting definitions overlap (e.g. atom indexes in definition 1 is 1,2,3 and in definition 2 is 3,4,5)
	        the highlighting of the first definition will be applied (e.g to atom 3) with the color it defined. 
        </intro>
   
        <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules.</option>
        <option name="Column name for molecule with highlighting">The name of the new column, which will contain the result.</option>
        <option name="Highlighting - Active">Flag to activate the highlighting defined in the table row.</option>
        <option name="Highlighting - Type">Determines, if the indexes are atoms or bonds.</option>
        <option name="Highlighting - Column with indexes">Select the column here that contains atom or bond indexes.</option>
        <option name="Highlighting - Color">Pick a special color for highlighting. Use the default color to let RDKit decide.</option>
        <option name="Highlighting - Neighborhood">Flag to tell if bonds between two highlighted atoms or atoms around a 
        	highlighted bond shall also be highlighted with the same color. This is mainly interesting when highlighting substructures
        	based on atom lists.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table with RDKit Molecules and Atom/Bond List(s)">Table with an RDKit Molecules and list(s) 
        	of atoms and/or bonds to be highlighted.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Highlighted Molecules">The input table with an additional column that shows the 
        	highlighted atoms and bonds in an SVG molecule graphic.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
