<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>RDKit MCS</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Node to find the Maximum Common Substructure (MCS).
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	This node is used to find the Maximum Common Substructure (MCS) of a set of compounds 
        	using the RDKit MCS code. Such a calculation can be a long running process. 
        	Therefore, a timeout must be specified as part of the options.
        	The MCS of an empty list of molecules is undefined and results in empty result cells.
        	The MCS of a single molecule is the molecule itself (as SMARTS value).
        	All other MCS calculations are based on the specified parameters.
        </intro>
        
        <option name="RDKit molecule column">Select here the RDKit Molecule column to be used as input.</option>
		<option name="Threshold">Fraction of molecules that the MCS must cover. Defaults to 1.0. 0.0 &lt; threshold &#8804; 1.0.</option>
        <option name="Ring matches ring only">Determines whether ring bonds only match other ring bonds. Default is unchecked.</option>
        <option name="Complete rings only">Determines whether only complete rings are included in the MCS. Default is unchecked.</option>
        <option name="Match valences">Determines whether atom valences are used in the comparison. Default is unchecked.</option>
        <option name="Atom comparison">Specify here how atoms shall be compared: Compare Any, Compare Elements, Compare Isotopes.</option>
        <option name="Bond comparison">Specify here how bonds shall be compared: Compare Any, Compare Order, Compare Exact Order.</option>
		<option name="Timeout (in seconds)">Specify here how long the MCS calculation shall run at a maximum. Default is 300 seconds.
			There is currently no way to interrupt a long-running MCS calculation. Even if you cancel an executing node
			the calculation will continue in the background and will occupy system resources until it is either done
			or the specified timeout occurs. Use longer timeouts with care!</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="RDKit Molecules">Input table with RDKit Molecules">Input table with RDKit Molecules</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="MCS of the input structures">Table containing a single row with the MCS as a SMARTS value
        	and additional information (atom count, bond count and if calculation timed out).</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
