<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit To InChI</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
    	Converts RDKit molecules into InChI Codes and optionally also into InChI Keys.    
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Converts RDKit molecules into InChI Codes and optionally also into InChI Keys. Additionally, it
        offers options to generate extra information about the generation process (return code,
        aux information, message, log message) and gives the user the possibility to specify
        switches to influence the InChI code generation in certain ways.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
	        <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules.</option>
	        <option name="Remove source column">Enable to remove the specified source column from the result table.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for InChI codes">The name of the new column, which will contain the InChi code.</option>
	        <option name="Generate also InChI keys">Enable to also generated InChI Keys.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for InChI keys">The name of the new column, which will contain the InChi keys.</option>
	        <option name="New column name prefix for extra information">The prefix of column names, which will contain the extra information about InChI code generation.</option>
	        <option name="Return Code Column">Enable to also generated a column that contains the return code of the InChI generation routine.</option>
	        <option name="Aux Info Column">Enable to also generated a column that contains aux information about the InChI code.</option>
	        <option name="Message Column">Enable to also generated a column that contains a message generated during the InChI generation routine.</option>
	        <option name="Log Column">Enable to also generated a column that contains a log message of the InChI generation routine.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
	        <option name="InChI Code Generation Switches">
	        	Specify here space-separated switches, which need to start with / or - to influence the InChI code generation.
	        	Some of them make the resulting InChI code Non-standard. A good overview about possible switches can be found here:
	        	<a href="http://www.inchi-trust.org/fileadmin/user_upload/html/inchifaq/inchi-faq.html#15.14">
	        		http://www.inchi-trust.org/fileadmin/user_upload/html/inchifaq/inchi-faq.html#15.14
	        	</a>
	        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with RDKit Molecules">Table containing RDKit molecules</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Result table">Converted InChI codes</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
