<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode icon="default.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>RDKit Optimize Geometry</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
		Optimizes the geometry for an input RDKit Mol column and calculates the molecule's energy in kcal/mol.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			Optimizes the geometry for an input RDKit Mol column and calculates the molecule's energy in kcal/mol. If the passed
			in molecules have no conformation, it will be calculated. The optimization is based on a particular force field 
			and a number of iterations. It is also possible to turn off optimization completely by iterating 0 times. 
			Optionally already available coordinates can be removed in order to calculate new ones from scratch. 
			The following force fields are supported:
			<ul>
				<li>UFF: Universal force field is an all atom potential containing parameters for every atom. 
					The force field parameters are estimated using general rules based only on the element, 
					its hybridization, and its connectivity. 
					Published in: UFF, a Full Periodic Table Force Field for Molecular Mechanics and Molecular Dynamics Simulations 
					by A.K. Rappe, C.J. Casewit, K.S. Colwell, W.A. Goddard III, W.M. Skiff, J.Am. Chem. Soc. 114 (1992) 10024–10035
				</li>
				<li>MMFF94: Merck molecular force field. 
					Published in: Basis, form, scope, parameterization, and performance of MMFF94, Thomas A. Halgren, J. Comp. Chem.; 1996; 490-519
				</li>
				<li>MMFF94S: Static variant of MMFF94. MMFF94S incorporates altered out of plane bending parameters that yield planar (or nearly planar) energy-minimized geometries 
					at unstrained delocalized trigonal nitrogen centers.
					Published in: MMFF VI. MMFF94s option for energy minimization studies, Thomas A. Halgren; 1999; J. Comput. Chem., 20: 720–729
				</li>
			</ul>	
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
	        <option name="RDKit Mol column">The input column with RDKit Molecules.</option>
	        <option name="Force field">The force field type that shall be used for optimization.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for optimized molecule">The name of the new column, which will contain the optimized molecule.</option>
	        <option name="Remove source column">Set to true to remove the specified source column from the result table.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for converge information">The name of the new column, which will contain a flag to tell whether the optimized molecule is converged.
	        	If iterations were set to 0 (no optimization) this value will always be false.</option>
	        <option name="New column name for energy information">The name of the new column, which will contain the energy value of the optimized molecule in kcal/mol.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
	        <option name="Iterations">Number of iterations to use for optimization. If the number is set too small,
	        	molecules will not be fully converged. Set it to 0 iterations to skip optimizing and only calculate the energy value.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Remove starting coordinates before optimizing the molecule">Set to true to remove coordinates before starting the optimization process.
	        	This may affect the results in a positive way.
	        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table with RDKit Molecules">The molecules to optimize the geometry for</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Result table">Optimized molecules with converge and energy information (kcal/mol)</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
